# UKANDIE SUNDAY

Front End Web Developer

♥ Uyo, Nigeria 🤳 +2349053588942 💌 ukandieudo202@gmail.com 📊 Visit my LinkedIn

ukandieudo202@gmail.com Visit my GitHub Visit my LinkedIn Visit my portfolio

# Summary

I'm Ukandie, a creative Front End Developer with over two years of experience. I consistently learn and contribute to teams, driving good results. I'm proficient in responsive web development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Tailwind and Sass, .

## Education

## Federal University of Ndufu Alike(AE-FUNAI), Ebonyi State, Nigeria. .

2017 - 2021

Bachelor's Degree in Accounting.

Abakaliki, Ebonyi State

# Work Experience

Moregift

Jan 2024 – June 2024

Front End Developer, Intern — Remote (Canada)

- Developed web applications with efficient and maintainable code using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Built responsive and user-friendly interfaces with frontend frameworks like React.js and Next.js.
- Documented development processes and project progress.
- Assisted in building complex features and troubleshooting issues within the codebase.
- Collaborated with design and backend teams to integrate frontend features.

Solacatech Aug 2024 – Present

Junior Front End Developer, Contract — Remote (Nigeria)

- Implemented best practices for performance optimization and SEO principles.
- Tested and debugged website for efficiency and cross-browser compatibility.
- Integrated backend technologies such as RESTful APIs, Node.js and Python .
- Translated design wireframes into functional code and interfaces.
- Maintained version control using Git and GitHub.
- Participated in code reviews, daily stand-ups, and agile development processes.
- Set up project environments and configured tools like Webpack, Babel, and ESLint.
- Kept up-to-date with frontend technology trends.

## **Projects**

#### E-Commerce Website | React.js, CSS, Redux Link

May 2023

- This e-commerce website allows users to purchase cars, including seamless features such as add to cart functionality.
- Various navigation views, user authentication, and privacy measures.

## Blog Website | React.js, CSS, Context API, Material UI Link

August 2023

- Blog Website: In this versatile blog website, you stay informed and entertained. Check the latest weather updates.
- Read dynamic engaging posts on various topics, and dive deeper into single posts for detailed insights.

#### Moregift's Financial Portal Website | Next.js, TypeScript, Sass, Material UI Link

Feb. 2024

• This website informs end users about the financial services offered and provides navigation to the mobile app for full service access. User-friendly interface, real-time updates on financial products.

## Moregift's Web App | Next.js, TypeScript, Sass, Material UI

May 2024

- I collaborated with the team to create the web app. This application allows users to create greeting cards, schedule, send gift cash, and receive gift cash.
- User authentication system and managed user privacy.

#### Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript.

Frameworks/Libaries: React.js, Next.js, Sass, Tailwind Css, Redux, Context, Material UI,

Tools: Figma, Katalon Studio, Jira, Swagger UI, Git, GitHub, PostMan,

Soft Skills: Analytical skills, Problem-solving, Time management, Effective communication, Team spirit, Creativity